> Lucas Gustavo Santana Silva

lucas2.2@live.com - São Paulo - Brazil

Profile

Lucas Santana is a Full Stack Developer, did his first job at eleven years and keep passionate in this area. Has expertise in JavaScript, back and front-end applications, cares a lot about user experience, better practices and newly technologies to escalate applications. And in this way, he help companies to make useful and cheaper applications using Container based applications, and Hybrid Cloud solutions. He likes to be engaged in the community watching live streams and conferences for developers.

Experience

10/2018 - actual

Full Stack Developer | NTT Ltd. | São Paulo - Remote

At this job I was hired to implement solutions for an product to automate company business. I've been a time implementing for this product called 'Fluig', after some experiencies, I realized that I was creating things that are no scalable and depending a lot from TOTVS to fix bugs and keep development. So I started to develop using Node.JS, Container Based applications, SPAs and APIs, to an internal NTT product, gaining more scalability and significant performance improvement in relation to the product that I used to implement (Fluig – a Java Monolithic application). I achieved a great gain to the company developing internal systems integration using WebSockets, mainly for communicate with Oracle, with the main goal to automate NTT business process in a digital transformation project.

Principal Technologies: Node.js, Javascript, TypeScript, APIs, Integrations, Angular, Java, Oracle DB, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Linux based servers, AWS, Continuous Integration, BPM, Scrum.

10/2016 - 09/2018

IT Intern | Acer Brazil | São Paulo

Hired to IT Infrastructure Support, but also I developed internal systems. A managing system for internal Sales, IT Helpdesk System, and also a new intranet portal, having gains in managing internal sales to employees, also improve supporting users.

Principal Technologies: BPM, HTML5,CSS3,JavaScript & JQuery

10/2015 - 10/2016

Jovem Aprendiz | PROMESP | São Paulo

In this job I was hired to scan medical record, but proactiavely started to manage local servers from the company and also support IT and systems.

Principal Technologies: Windows Server

Education

• Science Computer bachelor's degree - 2016-01/2019-12.

References

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucasgustavosantana/
- https://github.com/lucaslk10